stuartstirling.com 2018-10-02

# Privacy Policy | StuartStirling.com

## This page explains the Privacy policy of this site and all sites owned by Stuart Stirling.

By continuing to browse and use this website, you are agreeing to comply with and be bound by the following **Privacy Policy** , which together with our [Terms of Service](http://stuartstirling.com/terms-of-service/) govern Stuart Stirling’s relationship with you in relation to this website.

If you disagree with any part of these terms and conditions, please discontinue the use of our website immediately.

The term ‘Stuart Stirling’ or ‘us’ or ‘we’ refers to the owner of the website. The term ‘you’ refers to the user or viewer of our website.

## Who we are

Our business name is “Stuart Stirling” (a registered business name in Japan). We are a small online based business in the field of digital information marketing. This website address is: http://stuartstirling.com and this Privacy policy is in regard to all websites owned and run by “Stuart Stirling”.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Name, Email, IP address

When a user signs up to access free content or purchases a product, the primary data we collect is their name, email address, IP. We store emails and names in a database to send automated emails and instant broadcast emails to communicate information, updates and offers.  We use the IP address as a way to roughly record where the user is located (country, city) and to use cookies to serve personalized messages and website functions.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

If you use the contact form on a site, we will collect the information that you enter into the contact form fields (e.g. name, email, message) along with IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection where there is a spam detection function in place.

### Cookies

### **What are cookies?**

A cookie is a small text file that a website will save on your local machine (if you have cookies enabled) when you visit the site. It lets websites to remember the actions you took (such as forms you filled, login, language settings,) for a period of time. This helps to save you from logging in, and changing settings every time you visit the site. It makes browsing easier.

### These are the cookies set by our site(s)

**Social Website Cookies**  
This is so you can easily “Like” or share our content on Facebook, Twitter and so forth with the use of social sharing buttons on our site.

The privacy implications on this will vary for each social network and will be dependent on your privacy settings inside of these social networks.

**Site Improvement Cookies**  
To test designs or site features on our site, we show different versions of our webpages to different visitors. We anonymously monitor how our site visitors respond to different versions. This helps us to offer everyone a better web page.

**Visitor Statistics Cookies**  
We use cookies to track statistics such as website visitor numbers, their device and browser of choice (e.g. Mac or Windows), how much time they spend on the site, what links they’re clicking on, etc. This helps us to optimize our sites and web pages. These are called “analytics” programs and also tell us how people found our web site (e.g. from a search engine, or from another website) and if they are a return visitor or not.

**Remarketing Cookies**  
Many web advertisers, including ourselves set up ads to re-target users which have visited one of our sites or pages. This is made possible by using a “remarketing cookie” during your visit to our web page. We use these adverts to remind you and encourage you to come back to our site. You can opt out of these cookies at anytime by contacting us (see contact info below).

**Affiliate Cookies**  
We have partners (called affiliate) who promote our products and services on an reward-basis. When the affiliates direct you to our site, they use a Cookie which is to allow proper tracking of sales/actions so as we can reward the partner accurately. These cookies are usually provided by third-party companies (typically known as affiliate networks). Your personal identity is not accessible with the use of affiliate cookies. We ask you to allow affiliate cookies, because having affiliates promote our sites is the way we can stay in business.

**Email Cookies**  
Most of my sites offer a newsletter or email subscription service when you opt-in for a free product or purchase a product. Cookies may be used to track the actions you take on that email (e.g. open the email, click a link). This helps us to send you more relevant content.

**How can you control Cookies?**  
You can manage cookies that are set on your Computer or device freely. For details, see [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).

In your browser settings, you can delete all or selected cookies that currently exist on your computer at any time. You can also set most web browsers to reject cookies from being placed in the first place. But without cookies set, you may have to make adjustments manually for each site you visit. Also, some functionalities may not work any more.

**Comment Cookies  
**If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles, posts, and pages on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, banner ads, widgets, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to monitor and track website visitors’ usage of our site(s). They collect your data such as cookies and usage data. See their [privacy policy here](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). See[ Opt-out page here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

We use Facebook analytics (pixel) and conversion tracking to create re-targeting and behavioral based marketing ad campaigns. They collect your data such as cookies and usage data. See their [privacy policy here](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

We use Click Magick to track usage of links on our sites and inside emails and other media (e.g. PDF ebooks, videos, etc.) and to track conversions. See their [privacy policy here](https://www.clickmagick.com/privacy.cgi).

## Who we share your data with

As mentioned above, Google, Facebook and ClickMagick are third-party companies which we share your data with. In addition, there are other third-party resources which we use and share your data with. Including…

Aweber.com – We use Aweber to collect and manage lead and customer data. See their [data processing policy here](https://www.aweber.com/dpst.htm)

Zaxaa.com – We use Zaxaa cart and Beats email marketing system to manage lead and customer data. See their [Privacy policy here](https://www.zaxaa.com/privacy-policy)

WarriorPlus – We use Warrior plus to manage lead and customer data. Read their [Terms of Service here](https://warriorplus.com/legal/tos.php)

Paypal – We use Paypal as our payment processor for managing payments and managing customer information. See their [full privacy policy here](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

## How long we retain your data

For users that register an account on our website (by opting in with your name and/or email address or making a purchase), we also store the personal information they provide in the sign up process and information use to make a purchase.  All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information which is stored at any time (except they cannot change their username – contact the site admin if a username change is required) either within the website account user panel or when this ability is not available, by making a request to the site admin to remove or make changes. Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or another owned by Stuart Stirling, or have opted-in with your name and/or email, made a purchase, left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us.

You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

We send your data to our own databases which exist on our hosting company’s systems. We use Knownhost (see [Knownhost privacy policy here](https://www.knownhost.com/privacy-policy.html).) and Namecheap (see [Namecheap hosting privacy policy here](https://www.namecheap.com/legal/hosting/privacy-policy.aspx)) hosting for our websites.

Depending on your actions on our site(s) your data may also be sent to various third-party companies. Please see the above section on “Analytics” and “Who we share your data with” for information on where your data is sent.

Visitor comments on blogs may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### How we protect your data

We use highly secure, top of the line web hosting and third-party data management systems (CRM) to store our users data.

We use secured and encrypted web connections (SSL) on our websites which ensures your private data is securely shared and stored on our server.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

In the event of a breach, we will take the necessary steps to 1) alert affected users, 2) assess the scope of the breach and any potential harm it may cause the affected users, 3) inform users of required action 4) send updates of the resolution of the matter.

## Contact information

For any inquiries or questions regarding our policy, or to have your data removed from our site(s) or third-party sites related to this site, please contact us at the Support desk: [https://stuartstirlingsupport.com](https://stuartstirlingsupport.com/)

Policy Last Revised: May 25th 2018

**Copyright Stuart Stirling, All rights reserved.**  
Unauthorized duplication or publication of any materials from this Site is expressly prohibited.
